<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>码农日常这一块 • Posts by &#34;演讲&#34; tag</title>
        <link>http://example.com</link>
        <description></description>
        <language>zh</language>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <category>随便聊聊</category>
        <category>辩论</category>
        <category>技术</category>
        <category>创作</category>
        <category>演讲</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">http://example.com/2025/03/23/2025-03-23-ThreeGoGamesofLife/</guid>
            <title>Three Go Games of Life</title>
            <link>http://example.com/2025/03/23/2025-03-23-ThreeGoGamesofLife/</link>
            <category>创作</category>
            <category>演讲</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to introduce myself through the ancient game of Go. Just as a Go board has 361 possibilities, my life has been shaped by calculated moves, unexpected setbacks, and unbrokenable friendlyship—even when the game doesn’t go as planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opening phase of Go is all about balancing ambition and caution, however, I learned this the hard way. At 12, I lost my first official Go match because of reckless opening moves. That time my mentor said I was building castles on the sand,asking me to focus on fundamentals and stability. So I started studying classic strategies, practicing daily, and avoiding shortcuts. One year later, I finally achieved second dan. Go taught me that a strong foundation matters more than early victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The middle game is all about adaptability. Once, I faced a seasoned player who trapped me. Panicking, I made impulsive moves and lost. That time I froze under pressure and misread the strategies. But then I reviewed every mistake, journaled my errors, trained with stronger opponents, and eventually overcame my fear of failure. Go’s middle game taught me that defeat isn’t failure unless you stop learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go’s endgame taught me that even solo games need connection. When I was trailing by 3 points, my hands trembling, my childhood friend, who had trained with me for years, whispered, “Breathe. You’ve faced harder fights.” Her calmness calm me down. Inspired, I won by half a point. Later, when she struggled with depression, I returned the support, reminding her of our Go mantra: “Stones may fall, but the board remains.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life of me, like Go, isn’t about winning every match. My three battles taught me to value growth over titles. Today, I’m still a Go amateur—but every game deepens my respect for strategy, adaptability, and friendlyship. The board remains my teacher, reminding me: “&lt;strong&gt;A lost game still holds winning lessons.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
